# Kelly McCann

product designer & strategist

678.296.0465 kellymccann.design kellymccann91@gmail.com

## profile

Designer, strategist and researcher with development chops. Facilitator, relationship builder, systems thinker.

My background lies in Product: UX/UI design, frontend dev, user research, and strategy. I care about elegant, intuitive, and scalable builds, putting users first, scoping clear acceptance criteria, and cultivating collaborative relationships across teams.



## certifications

SCRUM Alliance - Certified Product Owner Hubspot Academy - Growth Driven Design Gymnasium - Atomic Design & Pattern Lab Writing for Web & Mobile Dynamic Yield - Certified Engineer

## education

University of Massachusetts, Boston -BA in Art, Studio Focus, Deans List & 4.0 GPA

## experience

### thoughtbot

consulting

Product Strategist & Designer

3/2019 - Present

Advise clients on design strategy, risk and MVP scope. Present progressive research findings and development work. Facilitate Design Sprints, define/maintain project scopes. Prioritize feature builds, conduct user testing, create prototypes, conceptualize and iterate upon visual designs, front-end development.

#### Richline Digital

eCommerce

UI / UX Manager

4/2018 - 3/2019

Product design, user research, scope frontend builds, oversee content management. Manage brand launches and CMS migrations, liaise with stakeholders to scope product strategy.

#### Content Manager

12/2017 - 4/2018

Manage content and website updates, create CMS documentation, generate mocks and wireframes.

#### MIT Office of Digital Learning

edTech

UX Researcher, Content & Communications Manager 10/2016 - 10/2017

Conduct and report upon user research, maintain customer engagement endeavors, manage CMS, content generation, social media marketing. Contract role.

#### Selventa

bioTech

Web Designer / Developer

3/2015 - 6/2016

All frontend design and development. Manage client relationships, scope acceptance criteria.

Assistant Project Manager &

8/2014 - 3/2015

**Executive Assistant** 

Generate mocks/wireframes, manage office build-out and office operations, liase with clients.